# Emma McDonald-Brown Software Engineer

#### Profile:

I am in the process of completing MSc Computer Science (Software Engineering).

This required the development of projects using Java and Netbeans, as well as creating this portfolio website using HTML5, CSS3, and some Javascript. It is deployed using Firebase. I also completed a cloud computing module, focusing on AWS and following the AWS Cloud Computing Architecture course, and an Enterprise Systems module utilising Azure DevOps for project management.

Currently, I am completing online courses in JavaScript and React, using Visual Studio Code, developing applications which can be viewed on my portfolio site. Some of these utilise Google authentication and Cloud FireStore, and are deployed with Firebase.

Source control is via Git/GitHub, with previous experience of SVN and Sourcetree.

Over 12 years' experience as an Openedge developer, mainly GUI but some CHUI, and database design and maintenance.

Nine years' experience of working in education.

Managerial and HR experience, as a self-employed commissioned operator, running a team of 18 employees, in a retail setting.

Portfolio: EMBDeveloper.co.uk

Github: https://github.com/emcdonaldbrown

## Core Skills:

- Progress / Openedge v8.3b v11.7 (GUI)
- Full development lifecycle
- Training and development
- People management

#### Education and Qualifications:

- MSc Computer Science (Software Engineering) (2020)
- Microsoft Office Master 2016 (2019)
- BA(Hons) Education and Professional Development (2018)
- Certificate in Education (2016)
- Mathematics and its Learning Undergraduate Degree (2011) (Not complete).
- NVQ Level 3 Retail Management (2005)
- NVQ Level 2 Retail (2004)
- NVQ Level 1 Using IT (1998)
- A Level Module results CCD
- 12 GCSEs Grade A D

# Professional Experience:

# Aug 2018 – Present, Pace IT, Developer

- Creation of user specifications and system requirements
- Business analysis and documentation
- Development and maintenance of systems for numerous external customers
- Testing and implementation of code
- Database updates and maintenance
- Agile methodologies
- Appserver maintenance and reporting.
- Jira and Confluence for Project Management
- Some JavaScript, JQuery and JSON coding.

## July 2016 - Present, EMB Training,

Self Employed First Aid and Safeguarding Instructor

# Dec 2003 – Present, Rita McDonald,

Bookkeeping, Admin, HR, Payroll

## Sept 2013 - Aug 2018, Barnsley College,

Essentials Skills Leader ILT Star / Advanced Practitioner Lecturer Lead First Aid Instructor

## March 2009 - March 2013, Carlton Community College,

SEN Teaching Assistant Voluntary Teaching Assistant

2001 - 2003, 2006 - 2009, Capita Hartshead Ltd,

Programmer/Analyst

## Dec 2003 – Dec 2005, Emma McDonald,

Commissioned Operator / Retail Manager

March 2001 - Aug 2001, Vibroplant (VP) Plc,

Programmer/Analyst

#### March 1998 - March 2001, Micron Technology Ltd,

Apprentice Programmer / Analyst

#### Interests:

Community First Responder / Scheme coordinator for Yorkshire Ambulance Service. Fundraising for local defibrillators, Restart a Heart, show jumping, online gaming, crafts.

### Contact:

Tel: 07814 031880

Email: e.mcdonald-brown@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/emma-mcdonald-

brown-bb187a28/

Location: Barnsley, South Yorkshire References available on request.